<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King the Kings most excellent Maiestie, considering what peril oftentimes ensueth by the meanes of great assemblies of people in the time of infectious diseases ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1606</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A22028</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8398</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S3667</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">33150721</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 33150721</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28726</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A22028)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28726)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1875:38)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King the Kings most excellent Maiestie, considering what peril oftentimes ensueth by the meanes of great assemblies of people in the time of infectious diseases ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
                  <author>James I, King of England, 1566-1625.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings most Excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1606.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>For restricting access to the court during the plague.</note>
                  <note>Other title information from first 3 lines of text.</note>
                  <note>"Giuen at our Palace of Westminster the first day of Nouember, in the fourth yeere of our Reigne of Great Britaine, France and Ireland."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Plague --  England --  Prevention.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James I, 1603-1625.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Court and courtiers.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:28726:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 7 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie, conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring</hi> what peril oftentimes enſueth by the meanes of great aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blies of people in the time of infections diſeaſes; Doeth therefore ſtraitly charge and command, That no maner of perſon, or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, of what eſtate, degree, or condition he or they bee, inhabiting within the Cities of London, and Weſtminſter, and the Suburbs of the ſame, or any other place where the infection of the Plague is, or hath bene within ſixe weekes next before the date hereof, doe preſume to reſort, or come vnto his Highneſſe Court at <hi>Whitehall,</hi> or whereſoeuer it ſhall pleaſe the King, the Queene, or the Prince to lie, or abide, vntill ſuch time as his Highneſſe pleaſure ſhalbe further knowen therein, Except the Lords the Biſhops of this Realme, the Iudges of the Law, his Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties learned Councell, the principall Magiſtrates of the Cities of London and Weſtminſter, and all Houſhold ſeruants of his Maieſties, and other neceſſary perſons for prouiſions of his Highneſſe houſhold, not hauing the infection of the Plague in their houſes, or neere vnto them, by the ſpace of ſixe weekes, as aforeſaid:</p>
            <p>It is alſo further by his Maieſtie thus prouided, That if any other (except before excepted) ſhall haue neceſſary cauſe to reſort or come vnto the Court from any of the places before na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, the ſame perſons ſhall not come within the vtter gates of the Court, vntill they haue firſt ſent vnto one of the Kings Maieſties Porters at the Gates, and to him declared, vnto whom they haue neceſſary occaſion to repaire within the Court, And thereupon the ſaid Por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſhall cauſe the parties to ſtay abroad, without entring into any Houſe, Tent, or company of any perſon, and ſhall certifie the Lord Steward, the Lord Chamberlaine, the Treaſourer, the Comptroller, the Secretary, the Vicechamberlaine, or any other of his Maieſties Priuie Councell, or ſome of the principall Officers of the Greenecloth, if the matter ſhall appertaine to the Kings Maieſties Houſhold, according to the qualitie of the matter, and of the perſons with whom the parties haue to doe in the Court: and by warrant in writing vnder the hands of any of the ſaid Lords Counſellers, or Officers, or by ſignification from ſome princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pall perſon about them, certified to any of the Kings Maieſties Porters, that the ſaide per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſhall or may come into the Court; then the ſaid Porter ſhall permit and ſuffer them ſo to doe: Otherwiſe the ſaid perſons ſhall be commanded to returne without any longer abiding, vpon paine of his Maieſties grieuous diſpleaſure, and ſeuere puniſhment in the Marſhalſey.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at our Palace of Weſtminſter <date>the firſt day of Nouember, in the fourth yeere of our Reigne of Great Britaine, France and Ireland.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>ANNO DOM. 1606.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
